const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"How is the immunity towards hepatitis B virus measured?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-HBeAb","bool":false},{"option":"HBcAg","bool":false},{"option":"HBsAg","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-HBcAb","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-HBsAb","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding split laceration?","answers":[{"option":"It looks like an incised wound","bool":false},{"option":"It can occur on the forehead","bool":false},{"option":"It can occur on the scrotal skin","bool":true},{"option":"It occurs due to sudden compression between two hard objects","bool":false},{"option":"It is a type of laceration","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding a stab wound?","answers":[{"option":"Its greatest dimension is depth","bool":false},{"option":"It results from piercing with a pointed weapon","bool":false},{"option":"It is a wedge shaped opening wound","bool":false},{"option":"In this injury bruising around the opening of the wound is seen","bool":true},{"option":"It may occur with a knife","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding age and color of a bruise?","answers":[{"option":"Normal at 1 week","bool":false},{"option":"Blue on day 4","bool":false},{"option":"Yellow on day 7-12","bool":true},{"option":"Depends on size and swelling","bool":false},{"option":"Green on day 2","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A patient with a duodenal ulcer comes to the clinic with a complaint of blood in vomiting. The ulcer has eroded the posterior wall of the duodenum and ruptured which artery?","answers":[{"option":"Gastroduodenal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Pancreaticoduodenal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right gastric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left gastric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle colic artery","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 9-year-old child presents with a prolonged history of abdominal discomfort, bloating, constipation, weight loss, and anemia. Serological examination shows positivity for anti-endomysial antibodies. An endoscopic biopsy of the jejunum will most likely show which of the following features?","answers":[{"option":"Villous expansion","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomembrane","bool":false},{"option":"PAS-postive granules","bool":false},{"option":"Villous atrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Loss of goblet cells","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is not related to an abrasion?","answers":[{"option":"Contain trace evidence","bool":false},{"option":"They are caused by friction of rough object against skin","bool":false},{"option":"Leaves scar mark","bool":true},{"option":"Radiator grill","bool":false},{"option":"Are superficial injuries","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"What defines a bruise?","answers":[{"option":"It changes color with time","bool":false},{"option":"It is caused by a blunt weapon","bool":false},{"option":"It is the extravasation of blood in the subcutaneous tissue due to blunt trauma","bool":true},{"option":"The weapon used can be recognized","bool":false},{"option":"It may help determine the time of affliction","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is true regarding a migratory bruise?","answers":[{"option":"May appear away from the impact site","bool":true},{"option":"May appear immediately","bool":false},{"option":"May appear within hours","bool":false},{"option":"May appear during re-examination","bool":false},{"option":"May not appear at all","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is  not true regarding a grinding laceration?","answers":[{"option":"Accompanied by extreme extravasation of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Caused by heavy weight with avulsion of skin from underlying tissues","bool":false},{"option":"May result in crush syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Occurs in road traffic accidents","bool":false},{"option":"May result from fall from height","bool":true}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is incorrect for an incised wound?","answers":[{"option":"Bleeds profusely","bool":false},{"option":"A wound with clean edges","bool":false},{"option":"The maximum measurement of an incised wound is its length","bool":false},{"option":"It is always caused by a sharp weapon","bool":false},{"option":"It Is always painful","bool":true}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is a disadvantage of the \"food frequency questionnaire\" method of obtaining food intake data?","answers":[{"option":"Influenced by food choices","bool":false},{"option":"Underestimation or overestimation","bool":true},{"option":"Inaccurate nutrient intake","bool":false},{"option":"Seasonal variability affects result","bool":false},{"option":"Ignore long-term changes","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is an indicator of a nutritionally at-risk adult?","answers":[{"option":"Voluntary weight gain of 6.5 kg in a month","bool":false},{"option":"Body mass index less than 25 kg/m²","bool":false},{"option":"Environmental pollution","bool":false},{"option":"Involuntary weight loss of ≥ 5% in a month","bool":true},{"option":"Seasonal flu","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A country in central Africa has high mortality and a high birth rate. The experts wish to classify the country's stage of demographic transition. Which of the following correctly captures the stage of the given country?","answers":[{"option":"Stage 4 (late transitional)","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 5 (post-transitional)","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 1 (pre-transitional)","bool":true},{"option":"Stage 2 (early transitional)","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 3 (mid-transitional)","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A country has a growth rate (r) of 3%. Experts want to make policies for better planning and administration. For this purpose, they want to calculate the number of years needed for the population to double, based on the current growth rate. Which of the following options captures the correct population doubling time of the country, based on the given information?","answers":[{"option":"100 years","bool":false},{"option":"23.3 years","bool":true},{"option":"70 years","bool":false},{"option":"35 years","bool":false},{"option":"140 years","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A man with chronic liver failure due to hepatitis B was brought to the hospital. His imaging reports show regenerative parenchymal nodules with fibrous bands and variable degrees of vascular shunting. Which of the following best describes the mentioned condition?","answers":[{"option":"Portal hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Non alcoholic fatty liver disease","bool":false},{"option":"Cirrhosis","bool":true},{"option":"Viral hepatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol intoxication","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is the effect of misoprostol on the gastrointestinal tract?","answers":[{"option":"Increase in lipid secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Increase B12  absorption","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in gastric acid secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Protection of mucosal lining","bool":true},{"option":"Blocking H2 receptors","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A patient presented to the outpatient department with a history of liver enlargement, pain, hyperbilirubinemia, and ascites. Imaging showed multiple venous thrombi in hepatic veins. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Fibro-polycystic disease","bool":false},{"option":"Budd-Chiari syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Primary sclerosing cholangitis","bool":false},{"option":"Cholelithiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Primary biliary cirrhosis","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is the side effect of magnesium hydroxide on the gut?","answers":[{"option":"Gastric irritation","bool":false},{"option":"Diarrhea","bool":true},{"option":"Constipation","bool":false},{"option":"Gastric ulcer","bool":false},{"option":"Malignancy","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A woman presents to the emergency department with a complaint of severe abdominal pain, and constipation for a few days. She is a mother to 4 children all born via c-section. What could be the cause of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Ulcerative colitis","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory bowel disease","bool":false},{"option":"Adhesive small bowel disease","bool":true},{"option":"Carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Crohn disease","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A patient presented to the outpatient department with reports that were positive for viral hepatitis. What type of jaundice can be seen in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Hemolytic jaundice","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive jaundice","bool":false},{"option":"Jaundice due to Gilbert syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Jaundice due to sickle cell disease","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatocellular jaundice","bool":true}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"In a clinically stable patient, immediate exploratory laparotomy is indicated in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Partial obstruction","bool":false},{"option":"Fractures","bool":false},{"option":"Penetrating wounds in thoracoabdominal reion","bool":true},{"option":"Foriegn body","bool":false},{"option":"Intestinal mass on CT","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most relevant statement regarding the H2 receptor blockers?","answers":[{"option":"They cause fastest healing of duodenal ulcers","bool":false},{"option":"They are most efficacious drug in inhibiting gastric acid secretion","bool":false},{"option":"They avoid first pass effect","bool":false},{"option":"They afford most prompt relief of ulcer pain","bool":false},{"option":"They are commonly used drug to decrease gastric acid secretion","bool":true}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 15-year-old boy with suspected acute appendicitis has an Alvarado score of 5-6. Which of the following would be the most appropriate next step in the management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Diagnostic laparoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Computerized tomography","bool":true},{"option":"Open appendectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Clinical management","bool":false},{"option":"Conservative management","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 40-year-old male presents to the emergency department with generalized abdominal pain and board-like rigidity. He has a history of chronic NSAID use.  An abdominal X-ray reveals air under the diaphragm. Which of the following conditions is most likely the cause of this patient's condition?","answers":[{"option":"Duodenal artesia","bool":false},{"option":"Boerhaave lesion","bool":false},{"option":"Mallory weiss tears","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenal ulcer rupture","bool":true},{"option":"Gastric ulcer rupture","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 30-year-old male is brought in an unconscious state to the emergency department after a road traffic accident. After regaining consciousness, the patient realizes that he can neither feel nor move his lower limbs. On examination, the gut sounds are absent, and the doctor suspects paralytic ileus. Which of the following is the most likely cause of the patient's condition?","answers":[{"option":"Colorectal carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord injury","bool":true},{"option":"Hypokalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypernatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Mesenteric ischemia","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 63-year-old male, who is a heavy smoker, complains of food sticking behind his sternum for the last 5 months. He has lost considerable weight and appears malnourished. Upper gastrointestinal endoscopy and biopsy confirm the malignant growth. What should be assessed first before commencing the therapy?","answers":[{"option":"Peritoneal spread","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan of abdomen and chest","bool":true},{"option":"Distant metastasis","bool":false},{"option":"Multimodal therapy","bool":false},{"option":"General health and nutrition","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"In Familial Adenomatous Polyposis (FAP), which of the following gene is mutated?","answers":[{"option":"KRas","bool":false},{"option":"MSH-2","bool":false},{"option":"MLH-1","bool":false},{"option":"APC","bool":true},{"option":"p53","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following defines a wound called Jurh Jaifah?","answers":[{"option":"Reaching a body cavity","bool":true},{"option":"Bruised margins","bool":false},{"option":"Having entry and exit wounds","bool":false},{"option":"Suicidal in nature","bool":false},{"option":"Produced by a knife","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 50-year-old man has been working in a battery manufacturing factory for the last 10 years. Now he is complaining of weakness, abdominal colic, constipation, and difficulty in walking. On examination, he has anemia, blue lines at the junction of gums and teeth, and foot drop. Which of the following poisoning has most likely occurred in the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Mercury","bool":false},{"option":"Arsenic","bool":false},{"option":"Copper","bool":false},{"option":"Lead","bool":true},{"option":"Iron","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 20-year-old girl is working in a chemistry lab. She gets into a quarrel with her fiance, who is also working there, and she takes some poison and she develops abdominal pain, vomiting, and diarrhea. On examination, her vomitus is greenish-blue in color. Which of the following constituent is most likely to be present in the poison she consumed?","answers":[{"option":"Mercury","bool":false},{"option":"Copper","bool":true},{"option":"Iron","bool":false},{"option":"Lead","bool":false},{"option":"Arsenic","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"The \"term ring\" fracture is used to denote fracture of which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Pelvic bone","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen magnum","bool":true},{"option":"Left Ring","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator foraman","bool":false},{"option":"Right Ring","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 17-year-old man is brought to the emergency department for consumption of acid.  He complained of a burning sensation in his mouth, tingling, and numbness of limbs with constricted pupils. Which of the following acids is the most probable cause of the presentation of the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Carbolic","bool":true},{"option":"Sulfuric","bool":false},{"option":"Oxalic","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocyanic","bool":false},{"option":"Salicyclic","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A young man while crossing the road is hit by the vehicle from the side and falls on the road. He is dragged for some distance. Which of the following types of abrasion on the surface of the skin is most likely to develop in this person?","answers":[{"option":"Imprint","bool":false},{"option":"Contact","bool":false},{"option":"Pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Scratch","bool":false},{"option":"Graze","bool":true}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Defense wounds with sharp weapons are situated in which of the following regions?","answers":[{"option":"Precordium","bool":false},{"option":"Forearms","bool":false},{"option":"Fingers and palms","bool":true},{"option":"Back of hands","bool":false},{"option":"Lower limbs","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is the primary impact injury in the pedestrian?","answers":[{"option":"Bumper fracture","bool":true},{"option":"Bird feet","bool":false},{"option":"Whiplash","bool":false},{"option":"Skull fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Jack-knife","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 47-year-old man with a history of NSAID-induced ulcers has been placed on sucralfate. Which of the following compounds is related to sucralfate?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium citrate","bool":false},{"option":"Aluminum sucrose","bool":true},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium carbonate","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium carbonate","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 49-year-old man with a history of peptic ulcer disease and gastroesophageal reflux disorder has been treated with cimetidine for approximately 20 years. He now complains of breast swelling and breast discharge. Which of the following effects is the most likely explanation for his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Neoplastic process","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory response","bool":false},{"option":"Overwhelming edema","bool":false},{"option":"Antiandrogenic effect","bool":true}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following drugs is ineffective in combination therapy for the eradication of Helicobacter pylori infection?","answers":[{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":true},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Amoxicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Bismuth","bool":false},{"option":"Clarithromycin","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most important drawback of sucralfate in the treatment of duodenal ulcers?","answers":[{"option":"High incidence of side effects","bool":false},{"option":"Poor relief of ulcer pain","bool":false},{"option":"Short duration of action","bool":false},{"option":"Lower ulcer healing efficacy","bool":false},{"option":"Drug administration 4 times a day","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 56-year-old female is presented to the hospital with an altered level of consciousness. After evaluation, she is diagnosed with fulminant hepatic failure. History reveals jaundice within the recent past. What is the most likely time duration of encephalopathy to develop in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Two months","bool":true},{"option":"Two weeks","bool":false},{"option":"Three weeks","bool":false},{"option":"One year","bool":false},{"option":"One month","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A histologist while observing an organ of the oral cavity under a light microscope observed a transition of epithelium from stratified squamous keratinized to non-keratinized epithelium. The core of the organ was made up of muscles. Which of the following is the most likely organ that he might be observing?","answers":[{"option":"Gingiva","bool":false},{"option":"Lips","bool":true},{"option":"Cheeks","bool":false},{"option":"Hard palate","bool":false},{"option":"Soft palate","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 49-year-old male is admitted to the hospital and is showing signs of impaired neuronal function, rigidity, hyperreflexia, asterixis, and altered level of consciousness. Further history and examination reveal chronic liver disease. Which of the following is the most probable cause of these, manifestations in the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebral infection","bool":false},{"option":"Vasoconstriction","bool":false},{"option":"Embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Increased ammonia","bool":true},{"option":"Stroke","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following types of polyp can be classified as neoplastic?","answers":[{"option":"Hamartomatous","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperplastic","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoma","bool":true},{"option":"Seminoma","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 28-year-old male comes to the outpatient department with a history of colicky abdominal pain for 6 months.  Pain is usually associated with diarrhea and abdominal bloating. He denies any history of fever and weight loss. Physical examination is unremarkable. What is the mot likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Reflux esophagiits","bool":false},{"option":"Ischemic colitis","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory bowel disease","bool":false},{"option":"Peptic ulcer","bool":false},{"option":"Irritable bowel syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 25-year-old female presents to the hospital with loose stools for 3 years. On examination, she is anemic, has glossitis, and marked weight loss. Investigations reveal Hemoglobin (Hb( 9 g/dl, mean corpuscular volume (MCV) 70. Upper gastrointestinal endoscopy with biopsy shows subtotal villous atrophy with intra-epithelial lymphocyte infiltrates. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Celiac disease","bool":true},{"option":"Intestinal lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Intestinal tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"HIV enteropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Tropical sprue","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A family member of a patient demands the doctor to withhold crucial medical information from the patient to protect him from emotional distress. What would be the most likely way to handle the situation?","answers":[{"option":"Document the request and keep the patient involved privately","bool":false},{"option":"Leave the room and let the nursing staff explain the situation","bool":false},{"option":"Consult your colleagues to make a decision","bool":false},{"option":"Comply with the family member's request to maintain trust","bool":false},{"option":"Explain the importance of honesty and involve patient in the discussion","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 3-year-old male child presents with a history of constipation and abdominal distension for the last few years. The plain abdominal X-ray reveals fecal matter contained distended bowel loops. A barium study shows a transitional zone at the rectosigmoid junction. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Malrotation of gut","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital megacolon","bool":false},{"option":"Small intestinal atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Anal atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Hirschsprung's disease","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 5-month-old child presents with a history of recurrent vomiting mostly after feed but never containing blood. He is on mother feed with alternate bottle feed. He is admitted to hospital due to vomiting. He was a full-term baby and his birth weight was 2.7 Kg. On examination, the child is irritable with a current weight of 3.1 Kg and bilateral mild crepitations. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Gastroesophageal reflux disease","bool":true},{"option":"Rumination disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal diverticula","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophilic esophagitis","bool":false},{"option":"Peptic ulcer disease","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"a 26-year-old female is suspected of having acute appendicitis. On examination, he experiences abdominal pain during extension of right hip while lying on the left lateral posiition. Where do you suspect the location of the tip of her appendix?","answers":[{"option":"Retrocecal","bool":true},{"option":"Pre-ileal","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic","bool":false},{"option":"Hypogastric","bool":false},{"option":"Post-ileal","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following inhibits the release of gastrin from the G cells in the antrum of the stomach?","answers":[{"option":"Vagal stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"Low pH in upper small intestine","bool":true},{"option":"Histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Distension of stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of amino acids","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"In response to undernutrition, the hypothalamus regulates the energy balance by suppressing which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Glycogenolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Satiety","bool":true},{"option":"Fat accumulation","bool":false},{"option":"Reproduction","bool":false},{"option":"Lipolysis","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"An 8-year-old child is nutritionally deficient and is diagnosed to be suffering from marasmus. Which of the following is most relevant about his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Enlarged liver","bool":false},{"option":"Good appetite","bool":false},{"option":"Edema absent","bool":true},{"option":"Normal height","bool":false},{"option":"Normal weight","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 9-month-old child was admitted for the second time to a nearby tertiary care hospital in Dadu, Sindh with severe abdominal cramps, and fever. He looked pale and skinny. The yellow-colored conjunctivae showed he had jaundice. Upon biochemical estimations of his blood profile, and liver function tests his bilirubin came out to be 21 mg/dl. The child is not responding to phenobarbital and sunlight exposure therapies. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Crigler-Najjar syndrome I","bool":true},{"option":"Crigler-Najjar syndrome II","bool":false},{"option":"Gilbert syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Hemolytic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Rotor syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 20-year-old woman visited the tertiary hospital in Karachi. The biochemical findings showed that her conjugated serum bilirubin levels were elevated. Her skin, nails, and eyes were yellowish. Later she was diagnosed with Dubin-Johnson syndrome. What is the cause of Dubin-Johnson syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Deficiency in uridine glucosyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Deficiency of aspartate aminotransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Mutation in MRP-2 protein","bool":true},{"option":"Deficiency of glucose-6 phosphate dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"Deficiency of Alanine aminotransferase","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 20-year-old man was admitted to a local hospital in Shikarpur city with Jaundice. His skin and conjunctivae were yellow. His biochemical findings showed the presence of Indirect, serum-unconjugated bilirubin (4 mg/dl), increased urine urobilinogen, and fecal stercobilinogen. However, the thymol turbidity test and liver enzyme levels were normal. What is the most likely type of jaundice the patient is suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Prehepatic","bool":true},{"option":"Posthepatic","bool":false},{"option":"Cholestatic","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"If a country uses such a method to conduct a census that only represents people who legally \"belong\" to a given area in some way or another, regardless of whether they were there on the day of census. Which of the following options best expresses the above method of counting?","answers":[{"option":"De jure","bool":true},{"option":"De facto","bool":false},{"option":"De jure method with some exceptions","bool":false},{"option":"De facto method with some exceptions","bool":false},{"option":"Combination of De facto and De jure","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A country had a sharp decline in births but that still did not bring an immediate reduction in the Natural Increase. Which one of the following options best expresses this phenomenon?","answers":[{"option":"Population Dynamics","bool":false},{"option":"Population Momentum","bool":true},{"option":"Population Pyramid","bool":false},{"option":"Population Transition","bool":false},{"option":"Population Growth","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A pediatrician asks a medical student to read aloud the anthropometric measures from the file of a 3-year-old boy patient in the ward. To fulfill this task, the student will read out which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray finding","bool":false},{"option":"Body weight","bool":true},{"option":"Stool report","bool":false},{"option":"Blood report","bool":false},{"option":"Urine report","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"According to the Gomez classification, all cases of edema are considered which grade of\r\nProtein Energy Malnutrition (PEM)?","answers":[{"option":"1st degree","bool":false},{"option":"3rd degree","bool":true},{"option":"Underweight","bool":false},{"option":"Fluid retention","bool":false},{"option":"2nd degree","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A mother visits the primary healthcare center with her two-year-old child and complains that the child does not eat well and is lethargic. On examination, the child has sparse easily pluckable golden-brown hair, puffy eyes, edema, relatively thin limbs, and protruded belly, along with skin rash. The child is most likely a case of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Marasmus and Kwashiorkor combination","bool":false},{"option":"Marasmus","bool":false},{"option":"Micronutrient deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Kwashiorkor","bool":true},{"option":"Overweight","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A scientist suggested the provincial government to\"establish a system to continuously monitor the dietary intake and nutritional status of selected population groups. He planned to use a variety of data-collection methods with an ultimate goal of policy formulation and action planning and improving population health\". The suggestion by the scientist best corresponds to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Food safety","bool":false},{"option":"Nutritional research","bool":false},{"option":"Food security","bool":false},{"option":"Nutritional surveillance","bool":true},{"option":"Nutritional assessment","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 30-year-old man presented to his primary care physician the results of his recent screening, which he did for an overseas job. The lab shows the presence of Anti- Hepatitis C antibody. Which of the following further tests should be advised?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasound Abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Complete Blood Count (CBC)","bool":false},{"option":"Liver Function Tests (LFTs)","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis C genotype","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis C Viral Load (HCV RNA)","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 20-year-old man presented to the medical specialist with complaints of yellow discoloration of the eyes for one week. Along with this, he complained of a fever and vomiting. He has a history of using un-boiled water. Which of the following initial tests should be ordered?","answers":[{"option":"Urinalysis","bool":false},{"option":"LFT and Serological Test for Hepatitis A & E","bool":true},{"option":"Blood Culture","bool":false},{"option":"Complete Blood Count (CBC)","bool":false},{"option":"Abdominal Ultrasound","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 45-year-old man presents to the family physician with complaints of pain in the abdomen, especially in the right hypochondriac region. The pain has been associated with high-grade fever for 7 days. Ultrasound abdomen shows a liver abscess size of 10 cm x 8 cm. What treatment is recommended for his illness?","answers":[{"option":"Antifungal medications","bool":false},{"option":"Antibiotics only","bool":false},{"option":"Surgical resection of the liver abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous fluids and pain management","bool":false},{"option":"Antibiotics with ultrasound-guided percutaneous drainage","bool":true}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 16-year-old boy arrived at the medical emergency department with loose motions for six months. On examination, he appears frail and malnourished. His complete blood count (CBC) reveals HB 5 g/dl, MCV 60 fl, platelet counts 5 lacs, and WBC 4000/cubic mm. Which of the following tests is recommended to diagnose the cause of his diarrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Colonoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Stool culture for bacterial pathogens","bool":false},{"option":"Serum celiac disease panel (anti-tissue transglutaminase antibodies)","bool":true},{"option":"Upper gastrointestinal endoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Stool ova and parasite examination","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 20-year-old man presents to the medical OPD with complaints of diarrhea, and abdominal cramps for two days. They are watery in consistency and associated with blood in stool. On examination, he has a pulse of 100/min, a B.P. of 100/70 mm temperature of 101°F, and looks dehydrated. Which of the following is the most likely organism causing his illness?","answers":[{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Rotavirus","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli (E. coli)","bool":false},{"option":"Campylobacter","bool":true}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 40-year-old male patient presents to the clinic with loss of appetite, nausea, and weight loss for the last 08 months. His lab reports reveal SGPT 120, HbeAg reactive & HBV viral load 20,000. ultrasound abdomen is unremarkable. He is diagnosed with chronic HBV infection. Which of the drugs is used as first-line treatment of chronic HBV infection?","answers":[{"option":"Daclatasvir","bool":false},{"option":"Tenofovir","bool":true},{"option":"Lamivudine","bool":false},{"option":"Peg IFN","bool":false},{"option":"Sofosbuvir","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 38-year-old female patient with gestational amenorrhea for 32 weeks presents in the ER with a sudden development of jaundice followed by an altered level of consciousness. On examination, she is hemodynamically stable, and deeply jaundiced, but not oriented in time, place, and person.  LFT shows marked Increased serum bilirubin with a marked increase in ALT, and AST levels. Which of the viral infections is more likely to be the cause of her rapid deterioration?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatitis A","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis B","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis D","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis E","bool":true},{"option":"Hepatitis C","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 42-year-old male, smoker, obese, came to a gastroenterologist with a recurrent history of epigastric pain and retrosternal burning not responding to conventional treatment, taken for the last 4-6 weeks. He planned an upper GI endoscopy which showed reddish longitudinal lesions extending above the Z-line, and multiple biopsies were taken. Biopsy showed Columnar metaplasia in the esophagus. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Achalasia","bool":false},{"option":"Hiatal hernia","bool":false},{"option":"Barrett's esophagus","bool":true},{"option":"Esophageal carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal candidiasis","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 28-year-old male came into the emergency department with a one-day history of loose stools\r\nand vomiting. He had ten episodes of loose stools overnight. On examination, he is dehydrated, lethargic, and unable to take oral ORS. He passed one stool in the emergency department which is watery in appearance. What is the fluid of choice for dehydration correction in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Lactated ringer (R/L)","bool":false},{"option":"Normal saline","bool":true},{"option":"Dextrose water","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertonic saline","bool":false},{"option":"Dextrose saline","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 35-year-old woman complained of a month-long, off-and-on burning pain in her upper abdomen, which was moderately intense. She also experienced nausea and had vomited once. There were no signs of black, bloody stools, or vomiting blood. Biopsy results showed she had an H. pylori infection. What are the specific conditions needed to culture H. pylori?","answers":[{"option":"0.5% CO2","bool":false},{"option":"Anaerobic","bool":false},{"option":"0.1% CO2","bool":false},{"option":"Aerobic","bool":false},{"option":"Microaerophilic","bool":true}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which microorganism is most likely responsible for the gram-negative bacillary infection found in the histologic evaluation of biopsy specimens from a 49-year-old woman with worsening epigastric pain and a 4-mm duodenal ulcer identified during upper endoscopy, despite no evidence of malignancy?","answers":[{"option":"Klebsiella","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobacter","bool":false},{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":true},{"option":"E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus Pneumoniae","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A hospital admitted a 16-year-old girl who had symptoms such as fever, loss of appetite, feeling sick to her stomach, throwing up, and signs of jaundice like yellowing of the skin and dark urine, as well as pale-colored stool. When her blood was tested, it showed higher levels of certain liver enzymes. Upon further Inquiry, it was discovered that she had recently eaten fast food at a nearby restaurant. Laboratory tests confirmed the presence of IgM HAV antibodies. The virus is transmitted through which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Needle stick","bool":false},{"option":"Airborne droplets","bool":false},{"option":"Blood","bool":false},{"option":"Contaminated water","bool":true},{"option":"Semen","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following serologic tests is most likely to be positive in patients suffering from chronic diarrhea due to celiac disease?","answers":[{"option":"Antigliadin antibody","bool":true},{"option":"Anticentomeric antibody","bool":false},{"option":"Anti DNA topoisomerase I antibody","bool":false},{"option":"Antinuclear antibody","bool":false},{"option":"Antimitochondrial antibody","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 27-year-old man comes to the emergency room with symptoms of acute intestinal obstruction. Examination reveals fever and a mass in the right lower abdominal quadrant. The patient subsequently undergoes surgery, and a segmental lesion involving the terminal ileum is resected showing a thickened wall and loss of mucosal regular folds. Mesenteric adipose tissue seems to creep over bowel loops. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Carcinoid tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Ulcerative colitis","bool":false},{"option":"Crohn's disease","bool":true},{"option":"Pseudomembranous colitis","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Salmonella typhi and Salmonella paratyphi A and B are bacteria that can cause severe illness by crossing the intestinal lining in humans, ultimately reaching the body's immune system. After an incubation period of 8 to 14 days, they trigger a systemic infection. What is the term used to quantify the level of pathogenicity of the organisms?","answers":[{"option":"Resistance","bool":false},{"option":"Pathogenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Infection","bool":false},{"option":"Virulence","bool":true}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 35-year-old man experienced sudden nausea, vomiting, and extensive diarrhea with watery stools, about 5 liters/day. These symptoms led to dehydration, circulatory collapse, and anuria (lack of urine production) due to the rapid loss of fluids and electrolytes. Which of the following bacterium is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Shigella dysenteriae","bool":false},{"option":"Enterotoxigenic E.coli","bool":false},{"option":"Campylobacter jejuni","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella typhimurium","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholera","bool":true}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most common primary liver cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatoblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatocellular Adenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Angiosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatocellular carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Cavernous hemangiomas","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A middle-aged female has recently gone through Endoscopy due to gastroesophageal reflux disease. Metaplastic change whereby squamous epithelium is replaced by\r\ncolumnar epithelium due to prolonged injury occurs in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Melanoma","bool":false},{"option":"Barrett esophagus","bool":true},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Budd chiari syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoid tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Upon abdominal examination of a patient, the doctor finds collaterals present as dilated subcutaneous veins extending from the umbilicus toward the rib margins. Sinusoidal dilation that occurs in portal hypertension is known as?","answers":[{"option":"Spider angiomas","bool":false},{"option":"Budd Chiari syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Fetor hepaticus","bool":false},{"option":"Caput medusae","bool":true},{"option":"Peliosis hepatis","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A patient presented to the emergency room with a perforated duodenal ulcer. Ultrasound shows that the perforation is present on the posterior wall of the first part of the duodenum. Which of the following arteries could be involved in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Splenic","bool":false},{"option":"Gastroepiploic","bool":false},{"option":"Left gastric","bool":false},{"option":"Gastroduodenal","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior mesenteric","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following enzymes is present on the brush border epithelium of the intestine that breaks down 1,6-glycosidic linkages?","answers":[{"option":"Maltase","bool":false},{"option":"Sucrase","bool":false},{"option":"Lactase","bool":false},{"option":"Glucoamylase","bool":false},{"option":"Isomaltase","bool":true}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 42-year-old female underwent an ultrasound abdomen due to non-specific abdominal pain. Ultrasound shows a well-defined anechoic lesion in the liver with posterior acoustic enhancement. No evidence of echoes within the lesion. The given explanation best corresponds to which one of the following lesions?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatic hydatid cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic cyst","bool":true},{"option":"Hepatic hemangioma","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic metastasis","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 13-year-old girl presented with severe weight loss, and recurrent episodes of diarrhea, containing blood and mucus from last year. There was also a history of lower abdominal pain as well. She has visited multiple hospitals and taken antibiotics but has not improved clinically. Her fecal calprotectin levels were highly raised. Her barium enema showed a string sign in the ileal region. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute gastroenteritis","bool":false},{"option":"Giardiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Celiac Disease","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory bowel disease","bool":true},{"option":"Eosinophilic gastroenteritis","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 3-year-old child comes to you with complaints of recurrent diarrhea since 8 months of age. The stools are bulky and foul-smelling. He was started on a complementary diet at 6 months of age. The weight is 7 kg. His Stool DR shows numerous fat globules. What further investigation you will advise to confirm the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Stool culture and sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue Transglutaminase IgA and serum IgA","bool":true},{"option":"Stool for reducing substance","bool":false},{"option":"Barium meal and follow through","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue Transglutaminase IgG and Serum IgA","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 5-year-old child presented with a history of abdominal distension for the last 2 weeks. He has a history of recurrent foul-smelling, bulky stools containing no blood or mucus. He was admitted to the hospital 2 times with the above-mentioned complaints, but not. improved. On examination, his weight was 11 Kg, height was 99 cm, edematous child with hypo and hyperpigmentation all over the body. There was no peri-orbital edema, heart sounds were audible. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic liver disease","bool":false},{"option":"Abdominal tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital heart disease","bool":false},{"option":"Malabsorptive syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 19-year-old male with a broken ankle after a fall was given hydrocodone (opioid analgesic) for pain. The patient had nausea and vomited once, and was given ondansetron to treat his nausea. What is the mechanism of action of ondansetron?","answers":[{"option":"H2 receptor inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"5 HT3-antagonist","bool":true},{"option":"Serotonin-norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"D2 receptor antagonist","bool":false},{"option":"Substance P antagonist","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which H2 receptor blocker has the maximum inhibitory effect on microsomal cytochrome P-450?","answers":[{"option":"Famotidine","bool":false},{"option":"Nazatidine","bool":false},{"option":"Roxatidine","bool":false},{"option":"Ranitidine","bool":false},{"option":"Cimetidine","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"Which of the following are the primary mechanisms by which prostaglandins promote ulcer healing?","answers":[{"option":"Increase bicarbonate secretion in gastric juice","bool":false},{"option":"Preventing pathogenic bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of gastric secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Increased turnover of gastric mucosal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Augmentation of bicarbonate buffered mucus layer covering gastro-duodenal mucosa","bool":true}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 45-year-old male is presented complaining of vomiting off/on for one month. CT scan abdomen shows a cystic lesion in the tail of the pancreas compressing the stomach. Which of the following findings is indicative of the benign nature of the disease?","answers":[{"option":"Cystic fluid amylase level of more than 3000 IU/L","bool":true},{"option":"Complex cystic lesion on endoscopic ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"CEA level of 500mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"History of mild upper quadrant pain at least a month ago","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of atypical cells in cystic fluid","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 30-year-old male presents in the emergency department with a history of severe abdominal pain. His laboratory investigation shows amylase of 3000IU/L. Which of the following prognostic factors is unfavorable for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"C-reactive protein of 100mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"CT severity index of 2","bool":false},{"option":"Ranson score of 2","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple organ failure","bool":true},{"option":"Transient organ failure","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 38-year-old female presents in the emergency department with a history of severe pain in the epigastric region and multiple episodes of vomiting for one day and gets admitted as a case of acute pancreatitis. CT scan abdomen shows a CTSI of 8/10. After 2 days of conservative management, the pain has decreased but she is not tolerating it orally.  which of the following routes is preferred for nutritional support?","answers":[{"option":"Total parenteral nutrition","bool":false},{"option":"Feeding gastrostomy","bool":false},{"option":"Oral feeding","bool":false},{"option":"Partial parenteral nutrition","bool":false},{"option":"Nasojejunal feeding","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 30-year-old female experiences an acute episode of right hypochondriac pain following a meal. She has had a similar episode in the past that was managed conservatively. On examination, she holds her breath on deep palpation of the right hypochondrium. On ultrasound, there are gallstones with pericholecystic fluid present. what is the best initial step in management?","answers":[{"option":"ERCP","bool":false},{"option":"Keep the patient NPO, start IV antibiotics and analgesic","bool":true},{"option":"Emergent surgical intervention","bool":false},{"option":"Place ultrasound guided cholecystostomy tube","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan abdomen","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 35-year-old male presents in emergency, with severe abdominal pain since one day. He has a history of pulmonary tuberculosis one year back. On examination, his pulse is 120 beats/minute. Abdomen is tense and tender. There is free year under diaphragm in erect X-ray. What is the next best step in the management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasound guided pigtail insertion","bool":false},{"option":"Conservative management","bool":false},{"option":"Start anti-tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Exploratory laparotomy","bool":true},{"option":"Colonoscopy and biopsy of terminal ileum","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2023","question":"A 45-year-old male patient with a history of hyperlipidemia and hypertension presents to clinic for a dietary consultation. He is concerned about his risk for cardiovascular disease and wants to improve his health. You explain the importance of the omega-3 and of omega-6 PUFAs in managing inflammation and improving cardiovascular health. Which mechanism describes how increasing dietary consumption omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFAs) in comparison to omega-6 PUFA can contribute to reducing inflammation and the risk of cardiovascular disease?","answers":[{"option":"Omega-3 PUFAs promote the synthesis of arachidonic acid, inhibiting inflammatory eicosanoid production","bool":false},{"option":"Omega-3 PUFAs inhibit the production of arachidonic acid, a precursor to inflammatory eicosanoids","bool":false},{"option":"Omega-3 PUFAS compete with the enzymes that convert arachidonic acid into eicosanoids (PG, TX, LTs)","bool":true},{"option":"Omega-3 PUFAs enhance the ability of platelets to release TXA2, reducing the risk of coagulation","bool":false},{"option":"Omega-3 PUFAS compete with the inflammatory properties imparted by omega-6 PUFAs","bool":false}]}]
export default arr